hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
talk about ways for you to grow in your
life your business to be able to reach
your goals make more money if you're a
coach or mentor and you've been
listening to this for a while with me I
help you know how to get more clients
and actually monetize that as fast as
possible today I want to talk about a
little bit of a different topic a little
bit more relaxed on this one it's the
holiday I like to go into something a
little bit more relaxed and I want to
talk about something that I studied for
a while that I think helped me a lot
what's the difference between teaching
and
coaching and that's what we're really
going to dive into and even what's the
difference between teaching coaching
versus Consulting and I think we're
going to bring together all three of
those so again maybe you have a
background in teaching I know a lot of
people who become coaches they make
courses they have a background in
teaching and they want to bring that to
the table they want to take that
experience of teaching others to the
table with a coaching business maybe um
you know you're listening this right now
because you love the teaching that I
share the difference is is that a coach
is able to pull out of people uh what
the action is that somebody needs to do
whereas a teacher um is is walking
people step by step through something
and it's transferring information now a
great online coaching business that is a
group coaching program something that
people can buy in a membership format
might combine teaching and coaching and
I think that by combining those two um
it provides a lot of great resources to
people you can resource them with
information as well as provide them with
the support and the accountability that
they need to reach their goals uh but
I'll tell you this is that we live in a
day and age with artificial intelligence
and YouTube if you're watching this on
YouTube or and podcasting teaching
is you
know teachers don't get paid enough and
and the reason why is because teaching
is just not something that like is
necessarily sustainable to be able to
just build a business by just teaching
people stuff and to my shagrin I I wish
that that was the case I find myself a
pretty good teacher when it comes to
teaching different concepts and stuff to
people but it's not enough to build a
business and so you have to learn how to
actually get people results in
transformation and move them just not
just from transferring information
but actually moving people into action
and this is one of the toughest things
that I've had to learn is that a coach
moves somebody to action they take what
does the person want to do what is that
desire that that person has what is that
thing that they're struggling with to
accomplish on their own and then they
don't just transfer information to
people but they actually activate that
thing inside of the person in their
nervous system to actually move and take
action this is again something that
um you either have it or you don't and
it's a skill that you have to learn over
time so the difference between a teacher
and a coach a teacher is imparting or
passing on information now great
teachers are actually coaches that teach
and coach at the same time and they're
not just passing on information but
they're actually also uh sharing from
experience they're giving practical ways
to make sure that they're doing it they
know how to motivate people they know
how to move people into action overall
in their lives and so great teachers
actually are a coach but they call
themselves a teacher again if you're
just somebody who says I have this
information I want to pass it on to
people that's just not enough and that's
something that you want to grow in that
skill you want to learn what is it that
motivates people what is it that drives
people what is it that keeps people
engaged what is it that that takes
people from where they are stagnant to
because most people are stagnant they
have a goal of what they want and
they're not going to learn something
because they don't want to not do
anything with it we're not in school
anymore people aren't in school they're
not just required to listen to you and
so you have to actually really learn how
to be that coach that person that knows
how to pass on the information and then
get people to take action okay now the
other thing is what's the difference
between a teacher a coach and a
consultant and this is another thing
that I that I learned cuz in our
business we have Consulting we have a
Consulting aspect we have a teaching
aspect and we have a coaching aspect to
it and you know for years I battled with
like what's the difference between all
these a consultant is actually taking
exact
stepbystep processes inside of an
organization or a business they're
working with somebody specifically to
help them Reach a goal and they know how
to move people not just into taking
action but they know exactly what action
that person needs to take now a great
coach doesn't even need to know what the
exact action is that people need to take
they can go on the Journey of Discovery
with the person and Discover it on their
own and then learn how to motivate that
P person to take action so a great coach
again can pull out of somebody inside of
themselves what they need to do to take
action whereas a consultant does need to
have that um teaching kind of that
understanding beneath the surface uh but
they also know exactly what people need
to do they know exactly what steps
people need to take so again in my
business I have a piece of it that is
Consulting um I have a I have a very
large piece of it that is a hybrid
coaching Consulting but I don't
necessarily call myself a teacher with
just you know students in what I'm doing
because I'm not just passing on
information I'm not just telling people
what to do but I'm actually walking them
through a process that they can apply in
their life and they can take action with
and so maybe you're struggling with
identifying what the what the
differences are with this you know
another term that people use is
mentorship mentoring somebody goes even
kind of above and beyond teaching coach
and coaching as again we're not
dictating to people but it's a lot of
people that are might be great
Consultants when they learn how to not
just tell people what to do not just
dictate but they learn how to listen
active listening and they know how to um
really come alongside somebody and raise
them up to a higher level that's what a
mentor is more like a fathering or
mothering type of a role with people
where it's like you're you're really
providing that like okay I'm going to
actually Elevate you and help you grow
in this area because I've been there and
I've done it and I've walked that road
myself and so again a coach can go based
on some Source material they can go
based on pulling it out of people a
consultant can go based on even stuff
that maybe they don't necessarily know
themselves but they learned they know
how to tell people what to do a teacher
can teach curriculum but a mentor really
needs to come from experience and often
times in my business I find that I love
mentoring people because I have
experienced over 21 almost 22 years now
experience in the online marketing and
sales space of taking people from where
they are to where they want to be to get
the kind of results that they want in
their lives and in their businesses and
I've been doing this for for that long I
say once January rolls around here it be
22 years in 2025 that I've been doing
this with people and so I started off uh
as a consultant and and as a service
provider that actually did work with
people and consulted them and that's
where I got my start in business uh and
then I started teaching people and then
I've started coaching people um back in
it was about 8 years ago no it was about
10 years ago I started coaching people
and now I I really feel like I truly am
mentoring people in their business but I
do wear the different hats I kind of go
in between all those like on this
podcast again there a very a lot of
teaching aspects to it um but I also
bring a lot of that experience so it's a
passive versus active form of mentorship
and so again just kind of knowing what
these terms are can help you identify in
your business what's the differences
that they make and how and how a lot of
people might perceive it as well and how
you might perceive your own identity in
your own business I'll tell you that we
want to move past just being a teacher
just giving people information and go
into where we're really truly raising
people up like a father or a mother
would or an aunt or an uncle and again
there's a lot of teachers that are
actually great mentors but they call
themselves a teacher okay there's a lot
of consultants and coaches that call
themselves teachers they call themselves
any number of these different things but
they're really doing one of the other
ones but by technical ter terminology uh
those are the differences that I've
found is that teaching alone is just
that passing on that information
coaching you don't even need to
necessarily have the source material of
what people need to do you can pull it
out of other people because your job
really is motivating that action in
somebody's life uh and then the consult
knows exactly what people need to do
they're more dictating what needs to be
done people are hiring them for that a
mentor is definitely not dictating but
they know exactly what needs to be done
because of their own experience and
they're not just teaching but they are
imparting to raise up others okay so
those are those the differences really
between all four of those and I think
that this is helpful for some of you
maybe you're a little bit more
analytical more of a FactFinder to be
able to use this in your life and in
your business uh to be able to kind of
know identify what that role is that you
take all right listen if you're a a
coach Mentor trainer somebody that wants
to do that uh in your own life and your
own business and you want to get more
results you want to get more clients I'd
love to work with you I'd love to help
you I'd love to lead you from where you
are to where you want to be in my client
growth accelerator program I work with
people every single week to get more
leads to get more clients in their
business and to make the kind of money
that they want to make and so I'd love
to see you as a part of that click on
one of the links Below in the
description deson and then we can start
that journey together we'll talk soon
have a good one
[Applause]
[Music]